renweb.com 2017-03-20

# Privacy Policy - RenWeb

### To Our Valued Clients:

The privacy of your information is important to us, and maintaining your trust and confidence is one of our highest priorities. We respect your right to keep your information confidential. We hope that by taking a few minutes to read our Privacy Policy, you will have a better understanding of what we do with the information you provide us and how we keep it private and secure. We appreciate your placing your trust in Wilcomp Software LP (“Wilcomp”, “Wilcomp Software”, “We”, “Our”, “Us”), the provider of RenWeb School Management Software ™ and RenWeb Donor Connect ™. The use of information collected through our service shall be limited to the purpose of providing the service for which the Client has engaged Wilcomp Software.

## Privacy Statement

Wilcomp complies with all United States state and federal law. For customers who reside outside of the United States, Wilcomp complies with the standards set by the relevant European Union Directives. Wilcomp provides a business service to our customers. Wilcomp will only use the information you provide for the purposes intended and as detailed in the Privacy Statement unless we have obtained your consent to use it for other purposes.

Wilcomp respects the privacy of every school and person that entrusts their information with us or who visits our website and uses our services. This Privacy Statement outlines the information that will be collected and how we will use that information.

We have developed our privacy policy from industry guidelines and standards, and local, national, and international laws and requirements. All privacy practices and methods described herein only apply insofar as permitted by applicable standards, laws and requirements. The fundamental principles of our privacy policy are:

  1. Data will be processed fairly and lawfully.
  2. Data is collected for specified and legitimate purposes and not further processed in a way that is incompatible with those purposes.
  3. The data collected will be maintained in a secure manner based on industry standards and best practices for the security and the protection of data.
  4. Data will not be shared with any third party without the consent of the owner of the data unless required in support of the school, or to complete a transaction on behalf of the owner of the data such as a payment transaction, or is required by law, warrant, subpoena or similar legal process.

### Information Management and Usage Policies

#### Personal Information Collected —

Given that our services include student information management and fundraising support, it is necessary that we store and maintain confidential information about the schools we serve, along with personal information regarding the administrators, staff members, parents and students associated with these schools.  _Wilcomp will not market our products or services to parents or students using this information, nor will we directly contact parents or students without the school’s prior consent._

#### _— School Administration_

We will respond to requests for Contacts and Sales Demonstration made via our website www.renweb.com using personal information received from you at the time of the request. To request information about our products and services, we may ask you to provide certain information including but not limited to your name, address, telephone number, email address, school name, school address, total enrollment, grade levels, and referral information.  _No information will be collected unless you provide it to us voluntarily. Wilcomp will not share this information with anyone outside of our company, subject to the limitations described above._

Wilcomp may use school information to contact appropriate representatives at the school. For example, we may send marketing or promotional materials including emails or other information to school administrators; we may respond to your comments, questions or requests for information; or we may contact you as necessary to provide general customer support. You may update your contact information or opt out of receiving marketing or promotional materials by contacting our Customer Support center by phone at +1 866 800 6593 , or via email request sent to [privacy@renweb.com](mailto:privacy@renweb.com).

When a school becomes a customer of Wilcomp, the school administration will be required to submit information regarding your business, its staff members and clients (parents, guardians, students and other associated parties). This information will be managed on your behalf within Wilcomp product databases by means of our software interfaces, the information itself remains the property of the client school as the owner of the data. You may request the complete removal of your information from our systems at any time; such removal will be completed within 30 days of our receipt of your written request.

#### _— Staff Members_

Wilcomp client schools will generally collect personal information regarding their staff members, including but not limited to tax identification, professional and academic credentials, and contact information. Staff members who wish to review or update their personal information may do so by contacting the school administrator responsible for maintaining such data using Wilcomp software interfaces. In addition, confidential information generated in the course of business, such as student evaluations and electronic communications, are acknowledged to be the intellectual property of the Wilcomp client school.  _Wilcomp will not share personal information pertaining to school administrators or staff members with anyone outside of our company, subject to the limitations described above._

#### _— Parents / Families_

Wilcomp client schools will generally collect personal information regarding the parents, guardians, family members and other parties associated with their students (e.g. physicians, emergency contact neighbors, etc.) This information may include, but not be limited to, employement, insurance, medical, religious, financial and contact information. Family members who wish to review or update their personal information may do so by contacting the school administrator responsible for maintaining such data using Wilcomp software interfaces. In addition, the school administration has the option to make available certain Wilcomp software interfaces which allow family members online access to review and update selected personal information.  _Wilcomp will not directly share personal information pertaining to parents, guardians or other parties associated with the family with anyone outside of our company, subject to the limitations described above._

School administrators have the option of making limited portions of their clients’ personal information available in various public venues, such as printed or online student or family directories. Requests for removal from such publications should be made to the school administration.

#### _— Students_

School administrators, staff members and responsible family members will generally use Wilcomp software interfaces to collect personal information regarding students, including but not limited to medical, insurance, financial, behavioral, academic, religious, demographic and contact information. Responsible family members who wish to review or update the personal information regarding their student(s) may do so by contacting the school administrator responsible for maintaining such data using Wilcomp software interfaces. In addition, the school administration has the option to make available certain Wilcomp software interfaces which allow responsible family members online access to review and update selected personal information regarding their student(s).

Wilcomp Software LP collects information under the direction of its Clients, and has no direct relationship with the individuals whose personal data it processes. Wilcomp Software LP works with its Clients to help them provide notice to their customers concerning, the purpose for which personal information is collected.

We collect information for our clients, if you are a customer of one of our Clients and would no longer like to be contacted by one of our Clients that use our service, please contact the client that you interact with directly. [If you are a Client and would like to update your account please contact us [here](mailto:%20support@renweb.com).]

Wilcomp respects all applicable national and international children’s privacy regulations. Wilcomp complies with the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA) (20 USC §1232g, 34 CFR Part 99) which is a federal U.S. law that protects the privacy of student education records.  _Wilcomp does not collect personal information directly from children, and any information we retain pertaining to students will not be shared with anyone outside of our company, subject to the limitations described above._

It is the responsibility of our client schools to utilize our services (e.g. the collection of information from students by means of customer-designed web forms) in a manner that complies with FERPA and similar regulations unique to the jurisdiction within which our client schools operate.

### Access to Customer Information:

Upon request Wilcomp Software LP will provide you with information about whether we hold, or process on behalf of a third party, any of your personal information. You may access, correct, or request deletion of your personal information by logging into your account or by contacting us at [privacy@renweb.com](mailto:%20privacy@renweb.com). We will respond to your request within a reasonable timeframe. Wilcomp Software LP has no direct relationship with the individuals whose personal data it processes. An individual who seeks access, who seeks to correct, amend, delete inaccurate data or withdraw consent to further contact should direct his/her query to Wilcomp Software LP’s Client (the data controller). If the Client requests Wilcomp Software LP to remove the data, we will respond to their request within 30 days.

We will retain personal data we process on behalf of our Clients for as long as needed to provide services to our Client. Wilcomp Software LP will retain this personal information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

The primary goal of Wilcomp in collecting personal information from our customers is to assist our customers in managing the information they provide utilizing our products and services. We have always safeguarded the confidentiality of information provided to us by our clients and are bound by our professional standards to continue to maintain this vital aspect of our professional relationship. The following individuals may have access to some or all of your information:

  1. **Employees of the company** : Employees who need such information to conclude a transaction or provide technical support for which the customer has engaged Wilcomp
  2. **Service Providers** : As with any business, other service firms may need access to certain information at very specific times and for very specific reasons. An example might be consultants that must have access to certain client records in order to increase the efficiency of our computer processing systems. We have and will always insist that any such information that needs to be disclosed for any business purpose be considered confidential and not used for any purpose other than the specific business need. That well-understood business policy of confidentiality will be reinforced as needed by contractual agreements with any service provider having access to your data.

Wilcomp will share the information necessary to deliver products and services that you specifically request to receive but we will limit this information to only what is necessary and required to complete a transaction. In certain situations, Wilcomp Software LP may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements. Wilcomp also reserves the right to disclose your personally identifiable information in order to respond to duly authorized information requests of governmental authorities, where required by law, when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, warrant, subpoenas or similar legal process. If Wilcomp is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our Web site of any change in ownership or uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information.  _Wilcomp will not share, trade or sell the personal information of our visitors or customers for use by any business without your consent.  If you do not want us to share your personal information with these companies, contact us here _.__

Wilcomp Software LP may transfer personal information to companies that help us provide our service. Transfers to subsequent third parties are covered by the provisions in this Policy regarding notice and choice and the service agreements with our Clients.

### Consumer Services and Contact Information:

If you provide our consumer service representatives with feedback on your experiences with our products/services or otherwise submit questions to our consumer service representatives or webmasters, you will be asked to supply personal information for our record keeping and follow-up.  _This information will not be disclosed without your permission unless required to do so by law. The consumer testimonials posted on our web site may contain personally identifiable information, but such testimonials will not appear without a consumer’s prior consent._

In addition, consumer testimonials and any personally identifiable information they might contain will be withdrawn from our web site within 30 days of our receipt of a consumer’s written request for its removal. If you wish to update or delete your testimonial, you can contact us at privacy@renweb.com.

### Aggregate and Statistical Data:

Wilcomp may collect and store web log information (such as your web browser, operating system, pages visited, etc.) to help us design our website, to identify popular features, and for other managerial purposes. However, web logs may also be used if necessary to help identify any person attempting to break into or damage our website, or use our websites to commit any illegal act. We may share web log information with law enforcement agencies if we believe that we have evidence of a violation of computer security or related laws.

We partner with a third party to either display advertising on our website or to manage our advertising on other sites. Our third party partner may use technologies such as cookies to gather information about your activities on this website and other sites in order to provide you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you interest-based ads, you may opt-out by clicking [here](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/) (or if located in the European Union, click [here](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/)). Please note this does not opt you out of being served ads. You will continue to receive generic ads.

## Our Commitment to Data Security

To prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the correct use of information, we have put in place appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we manage on behalf of our customers and the information we collect and manage. To protect your privacy and security, we will also take reasonable steps to verify your identity before granting access to information. We use secure connections to protect sensitive information during its transmission.No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however.  Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. If you have any questions about security on our Web site, you can contact us at [privacy@renweb.com](mailto:privacy@renweb.com).

## Tracking Technologies

We, Wilcomp Software, LP and our partners use cookies or similar technologies to analyze trends, administer the website, track users’ movements around the website, and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. Users can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level.

## Widgets

This site uses the “Share This” widget where personal information is collected in the form of the invite-a-friend feature. This feature is used to send a one time invite to the third party email address you entered through the widget. The personal information entered on this widget is subject to the privacy policy of the “Share This” widget.  _Renweb.com shares no responsibility in regards to the personal information entered through the widget._

## Public Forums

Our Web site offers publicly accessible blogs or community forums.  You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them.  To request removal of your personal information from our blog or community forum, contact us at [privacy@renweb.com](mailto:privacy@renweb.com).  In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why. ** **

## Links to Other Sites

Please note that if you link to a third-party site from Renweb.com, this privacy policy does not apply to that site. Even though you may have started your visit at Renweb.com, your transactions are completed with a separate organization and not with us. We don’t share your personally identifiable information with them, but information you choose to share with them will fall under their privacy policies, which we encourage you to review. We carefully select other organizations in an effort to give you the value and excellent customer service you expect from us.

## Social Media (Features) and Widgets

Our Web site includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

## Notification of Changes to this Privacy Policy

The most current version of our Privacy Policy will always be posted on our website at www.renweb.com. The date of the last change will always be posted on the bottom of the Privacy Policy page. If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this web page, our home web page, and other places we deem appropriate so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it.

We reserve the right to modify this privacy policy at any time, so please review it frequently. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you by email, by broadcast through our software interfaces, or by means of a notice on our home page prior to the change becoming effective.

Wilcomp Software LP  
820 SW Wilshire Blvd  
Burleson, TX USA 76028

## U.S.-Swiss Safe Harbor Framework

Wilcomp complies with the U.S. – Swiss Safe Harbor framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal data from Switzerland. Wilcomp has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement.  To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view Wilcomp’s certification, please visit [http://export.gov/safeharbor.](http://export.gov/safeharbor) Upon request and within 30 days, Wilcomp will grant individuals reasonable access to personal information that it holds about them. In addition, Wilcomp will take reasonable steps to permit individuals to correct, amend, or delete information that is demonstrated to be inaccurate or incomplete. Please contact your organization’s local Wilcomp administrator to change your personal information gathered on the Site, or contact our Customer Service center.

## EU-U.S. Privacy Shield

Wilcomp Software LP participates in and has certified its compliance with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework. Wilcomp Software LP is committed to subjecting all personal data received from European Union (EU) member countries, in reliance on the Privacy Shield Framework, to the Framework’s applicable Principles. To learn more about the Privacy Shield Framework, visit the U.S. Department of Commerce’s [Privacy Shield List](https://www.privacyshield.gov/list).

Wilcomp Software LP is responsible for the processing of personal data it receives, under the Privacy Shield Framework, and Wilcomp Software LP is responsible for the processing of personal data it receives, under the Privacy Shield Framework, and subsequently transfers to a third party acting as an agent on its behalf. Wilcomp Software LP complies with the Privacy Shield Principles for all onward transfers of personal data from the EU, including the onward transfer liability provisions.

With respect to personal data received or transferred pursuant to the Privacy Shield Framework, Wilcomp Software LP is subject to the regulatory enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission. In certain situations, Wilcomp Software LP may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at <https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request>.  

Under certain conditions, more fully described on the [Privacy Shield website](https://www.privacyshield.gov/welcome), you may invoke binding arbitration when other dispute resolution procedures have been exhausted.

For human resources data we have agreed to cooperate with Data Protection Authorities. Any questions, comments or complaints about the data practices (including without limitation compliance with data privacy principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, access, security, data integrity, or enforcement) of a hosted online OnBoarding software customer or partner for whom Wilcomp processes data should be addressed to that customer or partner.

This version of the Privacy Policy was last updated on 26-January-2017 and replaces all previous versions of our policy.
